[{"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What major challenges and problems did you face at your last position?", "answers": ["No matter how much you enjoy your work, every job involves challenges and issues you need to solve.  The interviewer will ask you about these to make sure that you are approaching this position realistically, not afraid of facing a challenge and learn about how you achieve this.  Your answer should reflect your ability to overcome challenges and provide an example of how you've done this in the past.", "\"Overcoming challenges is a key part of an application analyst's job.  Regardless of how well you plan a project, something unexpected always occurs and needs to be resolved.  While I don't look for problems, I enjoy challenges that require me to innovate and be creative to resolve them.  For example, I encountered an issue with one of my tools to analyze applications in my last job. It didn't integrate with the company's ERP system.  After some thought, it occurred to me that there may be an API available from the vendor.  I contacted them and confirmed that they had a solution to this issue.  I quickly integrated the API into the application, and it worked perfectly.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What are you doing to keep current with technology?", "answers": ["Staying abreast of developments within the IT industry is a daunting challenge.  Things change quickly, new products are introduced daily, and the challenges faced by application analysts evolve quickly.  You need to be able to stay ahead of these changes using a variety of different strategies.  The interviewer will be interested in learning about this to ensure themself that you will continue to have the knowledge needed to do this job well after you are hired.  When responding to this question, provide the interviewer with a high-level description of your strategy to stay current with IT developments and some of the sources you use to achieve this.", "\"One of the biggest challenges in this role is staying ahead of developments within the IT industry.  This takes a great deal of my time.  Fortunately, I am very interested in technology, so I spend time during and outside of work staying up to date on new developments.  I do this by reading industry publications, listening to blogs by some of the industry's leading influencers, meeting with application vendors to discuss what they're working on, attending technology conferences, joining local user groups, and regularly collaborating with my associates to discuss recent developments.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Can you describe the differences between functional and technical application requirements?", "answers": ["The two categories of characteristics related to an application are its functionality and its technical requirements.  The functional requirements refer to what the application is expected to accomplish, how it does this, and how the users interact with the application.  The technical requirements refer to the hardware required to run the application, other software it interacts with, and any other dependencies it may have.  Knowing this and describing it to the interviewer will demonstrate your qualifications for the job and your ability to communicate the key characteristics of an application to non-technical users.", "\"When analyzing any application, I look at both the functional and the technical requirements.  The application's functionality refers to the job it performs, its processes to accomplish the task, and how users interact with the software.  The technical requirements are related to the hardware and operating systems the software runs on, what memory or storage it requires, other software programs that integrate or interact with it, and other dependencies such as APIs, data imports, or interpreters required for the software to function properly.  All of these must be scrutinized to ensure the application will perform as specified and meet the business users' requirements.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What is your approach when you analyze and integrate new applications into an organization's IT infrastructure with limited resources?", "answers": ["In today's business environment, organizations have to accomplish more with less to remain competitive.  This requirement trickles down to every operation within the organization, including the IT infrastructure.  Application analysts are constantly being asked to do their job in less time and with fewer resources.  Not only should you be able to discuss how you accomplish this, but you may want to provide examples of how you've successfully done this in the past.", "\"In every organization I have ever worked for, the resources have been limited.  However, we still had to accomplish our application analysis tasks using what we had.  This taught me to develop repeatable systems which I could use to analyze an application and determine if it would fulfill the requirements of the business.  These systems incorporated processes and tools to help me quickly progress through my analysis, generate the required documentation, and communicate my recommendations.  I update these systems periodically to meet the evolving requirements or the organization and changes in the application marketplace.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Can you describe how you document your application analysis activities?", "answers": ["As with any profession, the job isn't done until the paperwork is finished.  Documenting your activities is a critical part of the application analyst's job.  There are several reasons for this.  The first is to create a record of what you've done that you and other analysts can use to review the work.  It also makes it easier to recreate the job or do something similar when analyzing another application.  The final reason is that there may be compliance requirements that require documentation.  No matter the reason, you should describe which of your activities you document, the system you use, and how to retrieve the information if necessary.", "\"When analyzing an application the business considers adding into their infrastructure, I document most of what I do.  My documentation includes the process I use for the analysis, the results I obtain, and my recommendations for integrating the application.  I also track my time which helps me analyze my productivity.  I store this information in the company's ERP system using standard filing conventions.  This makes the information available to other members of the IT team and easy to retrieve using simple queries.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What are the differences between SSH and SSL?", "answers": ["During an interview for an application analyst's position, most of the questions will be technical. You'll be asked about the wide range of technologies, applications, and information technology processes and practices.  The best way to be prepared for this is to review these topics before the interview so they are top of mind.  Researching the job posting and the company will give you insight into the types of technologies the employer uses and that you are expected to know about.  If you're unfamiliar with the technology they are asking you about, admit it, and then describe how you would go about locating the answer.", "\"Both SSH and SSL are encryption technologies used when connecting or sending data between two or more computing devices.  The main difference between these two is SSH addresses remote logins and controls businesses servers remotely.  SSL is an encryption protocol used for transmitting confidential or sensitive information, such as health data or financial transactions.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "How do you document the business user requirements when analyzing an application?", "answers": ["As an application analyst, you must always prioritize the business user requirements and how the application you are evaluating addresses these.  Documenting the requirements is critical.  This provides you with a record you can refer to during your analysis and will help you justify your recommendation as to whether the software meets the requirements.  The interviewer will ask you to confirm that you understand the importance of business user requirements and that you have a system to document them for future reference.", "\"Any application analysis project begins with understanding and documenting the users' business requirements.  This is the only reason the organization will adopt the software and add it to its infrastructure.  I spend a great deal of time understanding what the business users are trying to accomplish, the functionality they are looking for in an application, and how they plan to interact with the software.  I carefully document this by creating a needs analysis.  I then refer to this periodically while performing the application analysis to ensure that I understand the user needs and that the applications I'm examining address the business requirements.  Suppose, for some reason, the application I've recommended fails to meet the users' needs. In that case, I refer back to the needs analysis document to determine why this happened and whether it was because I misunderstood the needs.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Are you familiar with the tests systems engineers use to ensure an application\u2019s performance is optimized?", "answers": ["Determining whether an application is properly installed, configured, and is running appropriately can be difficult.  Systems engineers have processes to achieve this and a portfolio of tests to ensure the new application is set up correctly.  Even though managing applications is not one of the responsibilities of an application analyst, you should be familiar with these, so if an application you recommended isn't performing as specified, you can determine if this is because it wasn't installed properly by discussing these tests with the systems admins. The interviewer will ask you this question to see if you are prepared to do this.", "\"There are three tests systems engineers typically perform to ensure the application is functioning properly.  These include a load test, stress, and volume testing. Load testing places the application under a heavy load near the software's specified limits. This may simulate a large volume of users, data, or transactions. Stress testing is a methodology that exceeds the maximum recommended load to determine the limits of the application. Finally, volume testing verifies how the software will perform when processing standard amounts of data, user requests, and other loads.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "How quickly do you make decisions? Give me an example.", "answers": ["During an interview, interviewers will ask you about both hard skills and soft skills.  You use hard skills to do your job, such as analysis, documentation, statistics, and others.  Soft skills are not directly related to the job but still contribute to your effectiveness.  These include communication, collaboration, decision-making, and others.  Companies prefer to hire decisive candidates.  People who can quickly analyze the situation and make a decision are usually more effective than ones who spend more time collecting information, analyzing an issue, discussing it with others, and extending the time it takes to make a recommendation.  Demonstrating your decisiveness will better position you to be selected for the job.", "\"I consider myself to be very decisive.  I prefer to reach a conclusion and make a decision as quickly as possible.  I do this by collecting the information I need, analyzing the pros and cons, selecting a course of action, and moving forward.  I also consider alternatives and determine when I might switch courses if my decision turns out to be incorrect.  An example of this in my last position was when I was asked to recommend a hardware upgrade for our group.  I quickly analyzed our current requirements, projected how these would grow during the next 18 months, and determined what off-the-shelf hardware would meet our needs.  I looked at the total cost of ownership for three systems and chose the one that would do the job at the lowest cost.  This turned out to be the correct decision based on the performance of the system and the fact that it met our needs for the subsequent 24 months.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "As an Application Analyst, what do you believe is your best asset?", "answers": ["Many people are uncomfortable talking about themselves, their strengths, and their assets.  This may be considered bragging, and we've been conditioned most or lives not to do this.  However, you have to brag during an interview, talk about your strengths, and sell yourself to the interviewer.  Nobody else in the interview will do this for you.  It would be best to overcome your reluctance to brag and become capable of talking about your strengths and the benefits you bring to the organization.", "\"Some of my key strengths have always been my attention to detail and my organizational skills.  These have helped me immensely in my role as an application analyst.  Taking an organized approach to analyzing an application, being attentive to details, and noting anything extraordinary has helped me recommend applications that will benefit the organization and avoid ones that would be detrimental or not perform a function for which they are being considered.  My attention to detail also helps me understand the business users' needs and identify applications to address these.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "How do you help the systems support team troubleshoot an application that has crashed?", "answers": ["While it is not the primary responsibility of an application analyst to resolve issues with applications once they have been put into production, you may be called upon to assist the systems support team.  The interviewer is interested in how you would do this and what contributions you can make to the organization outside of your normal duties.  You can briefly describe how you would do this, the benefits you would bring to the organization, and possibly provide an example of how you've done it in the past.", "\"My primary responsibility as an application analyst is to analyze perspective applications the organization is considering implementing and make recommendations regarding their suitability.  This provides may a great deal of in-depth knowledge about the application.  The system support team frequently calls on me to consult with them if an application fails or isn't performing per the specifications. I'm more than happy to do this for two reasons. The first is it helps the organization get the application back into production as quickly as possible.  The second is that I learn even more about the application, possible flaws I overlooked, and ways to remediate these.  This type of work adds to my body of knowledge and my expertise in this field.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What is the function of a DHCP server?", "answers": ["As an application analyst, you need to be familiar with a wide range of different software and applications.  These include business applications, system tools, networking applications, and many more.  When preparing for the interview, you can anticipate the type of applications you will be asked about by reviewing the job posting to understand the requirements and expectations thoroughly.  You can also research the company to understand its business practices and the types of applications they use.", "\"The key function of a DHCP server is to manage the network users, configuring their systems and assigning them addresses and identities.  It is used primarily by network systems engineers to manage the organization's network and optimize its performance.  DHCP servers also manage components of the network such as subnets.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What types of firewalls do you typically recommend the organizations you work for implement and why?", "answers": ["As an application analyst, you will be asked to provide recommendations for a wide variety of software products.  These include system applications, applications specific to business tasks the organization performs, network applications, and other types of software.  You can be asked about any of these during the interview.  You may not be familiar with each specific application, but you should be familiar with and talk about general categories.  If you have never recommended a specific firewall application, respond to this question by talking about the firewall characteristics you consider to be important.", "\"When asked to make a recommendation about a specific type of firewall an organization should implement to prevent intrusions and fend off malware, I focus on the specific characteristics of the firewall.  These include the levels of protection they provide, ease of implementation, flexibility and adaptability, upgrades and patches the vendor provides to keep up with evolving threats, and infrastructure requirements.  Since no one firewall product is appropriate for every organization, analyzing the company's needs and the characteristics of the firewall will allow me to make a specific recommendation.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What are the requirements you analyze when deciding if a new project will support the company's business operations?", "answers": ["When beginning to analyze a project, the first step is always understanding the requirements that the project stakeholders are trying to fulfill and how to best achieve these.  By asking this question, the interviewer wants to learn more about your process for doing this and the specific items you look at when initiating a new project and deciding if it makes sense for the organization.  Your answer should outline the general requirements you analyze and how they relate to the business's operations.  Always keep in mind that your role is to optimize the information technology applications that the business uses to achieve its objectives.", "\"Whenever I'm beginning to analyze the effectiveness of a new project proposal, the first thing I do is query the stakeholders about the business objectives they are trying to achieve.  I then meet with the information technology team to understand the technical requirements of the business objectives and the type of applications that address these.  Once I understand the business requirements and technology, I analyze the functionality of the various applications under consideration, how they would integrate into the organization's existing IT infrastructure, and any other dependencies.  My analysis will determine whether it makes sense to move forward with the project and what its parameters should be.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "How adaptable are you, and how well do you react to frequent changes to business user requirements?", "answers": ["Information technology is constantly evolving, as are the needs of business users.  The user requirements you were presented in the recent past may no longer be valid.  The technology you're familiar with may become obsolete overnight with the advent of something new. Interviewers will seek to understand how flexible you are and how well you adapt to changes in your environment.  When responding to the interviewer's question, you may want to provide an example that illustrates your adaptability.", "\"I understand that I work in an industry that is constantly evolving.  This requires me to be extremely adaptable and able to change.  Staying abreast of developments within the industry helps me to anticipate changes and be ready to address them.  I also recognize that the needs of the business frequently change due to competitive pressures and developments within the organization's industry.  Again, anticipating these and working to stay on top of them helps me be ready to adapt.  An example of this is how I helped the company react to the restrictions imposed by the pandemic and the rapid move to remote work environments.  I quickly analyzed and made recommendations for remote work solutions that would facilitate communication and collaboration among a widely distributed workforce.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What ERP system would you recommend for our organization, based on what you know about our operations?", "answers": ["The interviewer assumes that you are familiar with ERP systems and their organization's operations by asking the question.  The interviewer will use this question to screen applicants who have not researched the organization before coming to the interview.  They can also use the question to understand your knowledge of ERP systems and how they are best suited to different types of organizations.", "\"Before coming to the interview, I took time to research your organization, its operations, and some of the technology you currently use.  I discovered that you interact with many different suppliers, have a high level of business transactions each month, and operate at several locations across the globe.  Based on this, I would recommend that you continue to use SAP as your ERP system.  If you haven't already, you may want to integrate some of the additional SAP modules to manage your production, distribution, and supply chain systems.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What activities and items do application analysts typically document?", "answers": ["Documentation is an important aspect of any job, but even more so for an application analyst.  Documenting activities, findings, and recommendations provides a record of the work that can be referred to as conditions evolve if the recommendation proves to be incorrect.  Documentation also helps processes to be easily replicated if necessary.  The interviewer will be interested in what items you document, the systems you use to do this, and other aspects of your record-keeping activities.  You should be prepared to discuss these and provide specific examples of your documentation processes and procedures.", "\"I make a point to keep a record of everything I do.  Information I record includes the products I investigate, my findings, recommendations I've made, and other aspects of my analysis.  I also carefully document the processes, procedures, applications, and tools I use to analyze any outside resources I depend on and the time I spend analyzing applications.  These records are carefully maintained in the company's ERP system, including related documents, images, and other artifacts.  Finally, I maintain a very detailed database of all the vendors I work with, their contact information, systems integrators and partners affiliated with them, and other industry contacts I have.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What is your process for assessing the organization's technology needs?", "answers": ["Any application analysis project begins with assessing the organization's business needs and how these can be fulfilled using technology.  The interviewer expects you to have a detailed process for your assessment.  The information they want you to provide includes what aspects of the business processes you examine, questions you ask the business unit leaders, and your approach to matching technology solutions to the business requirements. They may also be interested in how you stack rank items such as costs, ease of implementation, training requirements, and other factors which impact how well the organization can adopt new technology.", "\"When analyzing an organization's technology needs, I begin with the business processes and problems the business units are trying to solve.  Understanding these is the key to determining what technologies will address these needs and how easily they can be implemented within the organization.  Once I understand the business processes, I can then seek solutions to them which fit the organization's culture, are easily implemented, and are within the available budget.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What are some of the items you examine when performing an application analysis?", "answers": ["During an application analyst's job interview, you'll be asked many technical and operational questions.  These help the interviewer understand your qualifications, knowledge of technology, and processes you use to perform your job.  Learning more about each of these helps the interviewer determine if you are qualified for the role. Your answers also demonstrate your ability to communicate complex technical subjects to non-technical individuals using easy-to-understand language.", "\"When examining applications and analyzing whether they are appropriate for the organization, I look at many factors.  The initial items are related to the business processes and the business unit's issues with the application.  Once I understand these, I then identify potential solutions.  I examine each of these for how well they address the business issues, their ease of use, the reputation of the vendors, how much training would be required if they were adopted, how well they are documented, their interoperability with other applications, and how easily they are either upgraded or replaced if necessary.  Once I've identified two to three viable candidates, I look at their costs, including the initial purchase price and additional costs related to the product's lifecycle.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Do you feel that it is important to register the software the organization uses, and if so, why?", "answers": ["It is common for many organizations not to register the software products they use or maintain records for it.  This is usually due to neglect or simply not feeling that software registration is important.  By asking this question, the organization either seeks to ensure that you consider software registration to be important or are curious about whether they should be doing a better job of maintaining their records related to the software they use.  The best way to answer this question would be to emphasize the importance of maintaining accurate documentation for the software and describing a system that facilitates this.", "\"I feel it is critically important for an organization to maintain accurate records for the software it uses.  This is important for several reasons.  The first is that it provides the information a company needs to track the software it uses, ensure that it is licensed appropriately, have access to the support they need, and easily upgrade or replace it.  In my previous companies, we used a variety of systems to make this easy to accomplish.  These included its ERP system, the IT organization's databases, spreadsheets, and special products designed to document and track software applications.  Implementing any of these systems is far better than having no system.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "How do you evaluate existing software applications to determine if they are still appropriate for the organization's business requirements?", "answers": ["In addition to evaluating new or prospective software applications, one of the responsibilities of an application analyst is to review the organization's existing applications to see if they are still meeting the business requirements.  The interviewer will ask you this question to determine if you do this and what systems you use to accomplish it.  These processes will differ from the ones you use to analyze a new or prospective application.  They should be simpler, faster, and performed more frequently.  Your answer should reflect this.", "\"It is important to continually evaluate the applications an organization currently uses to ensure that they are still doing the job for which they were originally purchased.  I do this by creating a schedule for annual reviews of each application the company uses.  I use the process to provide the business users with a questionnaire asking them to evaluate the application, describe any issues they've had with it, and comment as to whether they feel it needs to be replaced or upgraded.  I also examine the support team's records to see how often they have had to respond to user issues related to the software.  Finally, I meet with the application's vendor to understand if there are upgrades available for the application, what benefits these provide, and how long the vendor is planning to support the current version of the application.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Please discuss the key modules in the SAP application and what they are used for.", "answers": ["Interviewers will ask you questions about specific types of software applications for two reasons. The first is to better understand your knowledge of the application and familiarity with it.  The second is to explore your expertise in analyzing applications and ensure that you understand the fundamentals and function of the application.  Your answer will also demonstrate your communication skills and ability to describe complex topics in simple, easy-to-understand language.", "\"SAP is a very complex application.  It contains roughly 25 modules that apply to specific business functions.  Therefore, some of the more commonly used and most important modules are accounting, sales and marketing, materials, human resources, maintenance, quality assurance, warehousing, and production.  Each module can be customized for a specific business and the activities they use SAP to manage.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What steps do you take to optimize the cost efficiency of applications and other IT assets?", "answers": ["The main objective of an application analyst is to help organizations increase the efficiency of their applications while minimizing the costs of the IT infrastructure.  The interviewer all be interested in the specific strategies you have used to accomplish this.  When asking this question, the interviewer is more interested in the big picture and the global strategies and activities you use to make the company's IT infrastructure efficient.  While you should avoid delving into the details, you can provide one or more brief examples of how you have achieved this in your previous positions.", "\"In my role as an application analyst, I am constantly monitoring and analyzing the organization's IT processes, applications, and IT infrastructure.  I look for opportunities to reduce costs by minimizing software licenses, upgrading outdated systems that have become inefficient, and aggregating resources that can simultaneously perform multiple functions.  One strategy that has consistently worked for me in the other organizations I've worked for is comparing the costs and benefits of integrating new IT assets into the organization's infrastructure with the productivity gains the organization would realize by doing this.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "What is the approach you use to perform a  top-down application analysis?", "answers": ["The top-down approach to application analysis starts with looking at the major functionality of the application.  Once this is identified and specified, the application's sub-processes and other functions are examined to meet the users' needs.  The interviewer will ask you this question to make sure you understand this concept and use this approach in your role as an application analyst.  Since this is the most common methodology used in your profession, you should be very familiar with and able to describe it.", "\"I have found that the top-down approach to application analysis is the most effective and efficient.  I begin by looking at the major function of the application and how it relates to the business requirements the users are trying to achieve.  Once I confirm this relationship, I look at the application's subfunctions and other lower functionality to see how these will impact the organization's business operations.  I want to make sure that these support the major function of the application and are compatible with the company's current processes and procedures and its technology infrastructure.  For example, if the application requires data from other sources, does it have APIs or other links with which to retrieve the information it needs to function.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Why do you want a career as an application analyst?", "answers": ["This is a typical opening question the interviewer will use early in the interview to start the conversation, learn more about your background, and collect information they can use throughout the interview.  You should be prepared for this type of question and other common questions used during an interview.  One way you can do this is to review these questions and answer them in your own words before going to the interview.", "\"I have always had a great desire to learn new things and investigate items and topics I encounter in my daily activities.  This thirst for knowledge and the ability to look at a topic's details helped me develop intuitive analytical skills.  I became very excited when I learned that my natural tendency to analyze things could be turned into a career as an application analyst.  When I entered college, I immediately enrolled in a program that would help me acquire the skills and background needed for this profession.  Once I obtained my first position as an application analyst, I knew I had chosen the right career, and I've never looked back.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": ["This is a common question asked during an interview.  It is a type of question you can prepare for by creating a script.  Your answer should discuss the benefits you will bring to the organization, the problems you can help them solve, and how you can help them make money, save money, or save time.  You may also want to touch on how well you will fit into their corporate culture and contribute to it.  Avoid talking about your qualifications, experience, and skills.  By inviting you to the interview, they have already acknowledged these and their fit for the position.", "\"The main reason you should hire me is I can help your organization optimize its IT operations and how well they support the company's business activities.  I can quickly analyze the applications you're considering integrated into your IT infrastructure, determine if they are appropriate, and provide an estimate of the cost savings you will realize by adopting them.  Once hired, I can monitor your existing applications to ensure that they are continuing to provide the benefits you originally purchased them for and, if necessary, recommend the appropriate upgrades or replacements.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Tell me about an accomplishment you are most proud of.", "answers": ["When an interviewer asks you this question, they hope to understand the scope of your accomplishments and whether what you've accomplished aligns with the needs of the position they're trying to fill.  Before coming to the interview, you should research the job posting and the organization to understand the position's requirements and the business's operations.  You then answer this and other questions within the context of their needs, so they quickly understand that you're the right candidate for this role.", "\"The professional accomplishment I am most proud of was when I was able to help an organization reduce its annual software budget by 25%.  I did this by analyzing every application the organization was using, identifying opportunities for cost savings, reducing the number of licenses the company was paying for, and upgrading the applications which had become obsolete or ineffective.  While performing the analysis, I developed a set of systems and tools that I've used for subsequent analyses. This has resulted in similar savings for other organizations I have worked for.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "How do you keep track of work so that it gets done on time?", "answers": ["Regardless of your skills as an application analyst, if you can complete your projects on time and under budget, you will not be effective in the position.  An interviewer will ask how you track your work to determine your organizational skills and whether you have a record of accomplishing projects on time.  During every interview, you should be prepared for this or a similar question and practice answering it, describing your methodology and any tools you may use to keep track of your work.", "\"Keeping track of my work during a project is a critical requirement of this role.  I always want to know where I'm at concerning the project timeline and ensure I accomplish my tasks on schedule.  This helps me stay on track and to finish on time.  I do this using both spreadsheets and pert charts and sometimes project management software.  I can break the project into individual tasks, schedule each task, and build buffers to accommodate changes or unexpected developments.  I monitor my progress daily and adjust my schedule as needed so I don't fall behind.  This methodology also allows me to schedule the resources and the external dependencies needed to complete the project.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Why are you the best application analyst for us?", "answers": ["This question is much like the one that asks why the organization should hire you.  It is a question you can be prepared for by creating a script.  This question variation allows you to quickly review your qualifications and discuss how well you will fit into and contribute to their corporate culture.  Every candidate the company interviews is qualified for the role.  However, every candidate may not be a good fit for the organization.  Focus on this when responding to the question.", "\"I believe I am the best application analysis for this job because not only do I possess all the necessary technical qualifications, but I would be a great fit for the organization. I've worked with several other companies similar to yours and understand the importance of collaboration within my department and across the organization.  I never lose sight of the fact that the IT organization supports the business operations of the company.  I work hard to get along with the other departments and communicate complex technical topics in clear, easy-to-understand language.  I also bring a great sense of humor which keeps the working environment light and friendly.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Analyst", "question": "Give me a time when you had to set an important goal in the past and tell me about your success reaching it.", "answers": ["Setting goals and attaining them is a key talent interviewers look for when interviewing a candidate.  A history of doing this indicates that the candidate can complete their assigned projects on time if hired.  Responding to this question with a concrete example of how you achieved this in the past will help convince the interviewer that you are the right person for this role.  Make sure that your story demonstrating this is relevant to the organization's business operations and the job requirements for which you are interviewing.", "\"At my last company, I was assigned to analyze a new financial application which the company wanted to implement on time to assist with year-end closing.  I was given less than 30 days to complete my analysis and make a recommendation.  To accomplish this, I had to be very organized, stay focused, and break the project down into individual tasks that needed to be completed.  I developed a plan for the project and executed it flawlessly.  I completed my analysis and made my recommendation a week early. The company was able to implement the software well ahead of schedule.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "Why do you want a career as an application development director?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "What major challenges and problems did you face at your last position?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "What motivates you to succeed?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "Have you ever had to fire anyone? How did you feel about that?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "How do you decide what gets top priority when scheduling your time?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "Tell me an example of a situation where you had difficulties with a team member.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "How do you keep track of work so that it gets done on time?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "What do you feel is the most important skill an application development director should possess?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Development+Director", "question": "What are you doing to keep current in technology?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What is your greatest weakness?", "answers": ["During an interview for any job, you will be asked about your strengths and weaknesses.  These are typical questions interviewers use to evaluate how introspective you are and how well you know yourself.  It also demonstrates your communication skills since talking about yourself positively or negatively is challenging.  When responding to a question about your greatest weakness, you can identify a weakness that is not related to the job, discuss something related to the job but that you are working to resolve, or talk about a weakness you formerly had but have since corrected.  The second of these strategies is the most effective because it enables you to talk about an existing weakness and demonstrate to the interviewer that you have a strategy to overcome your deficiencies, including any they may perceive.", "\"I believe my greatest professional weakness is the fear of speaking in front of an audience.  For some reason, I become nervous when I need to make a presentation to a group of people, even if it's only my peers. I'm working hard to overcome this, and it is getting better. I've joined a local Toastmasters group, taken some online presentation coaching classes, and worked with my supervisors to refine my presentation skills and build confidence.  While I still get nervous, once I start talking, I feel more comfortable and can complete the presentation effectively.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What are you doing to keep current in technology?", "answers": ["Staying abreast of developments within the IT industry is a daunting challenge.  Things change quickly, new products are introduced daily, and the challenges faced by application integration engineers evolve quickly.  You need to be able to stay ahead of these changes using a variety of different strategies. When responding to this question, provide the interviewer with a high-level description of your strategy to stay current with IT developments and some of the sources you use to achieve this. The interviewer will be interested in learning about this to ensure themself that you will continue to have the knowledge needed to do this job well after you are hired.", "\"One of the biggest challenges in this role is staying ahead of developments within the IT industry.  This takes a great deal of my time.  Fortunately, I am very interested in technology, so I spend time during and outside of work staying up to date on new developments.  I do this by reading industry publications, listening to blogs by some of the industry's leading influencers, meeting with application vendors to discuss what they're working on, attending technology conferences, joining local user groups, and regularly collaborating with my associates to discuss recent developments.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Describe for me the details included in your design for an application integration project.", "answers": ["Many details can be included in the design for an application integration project.  Many of these are standard, but some may depend on the organization or the application integration engineer.  An interviewer will ask you about these to determine which ones you use and if they are the same as the organization's.  Researching the organization will help you understand the details you consider in your design are the same as their current integration team uses.  If they aren't, be prepared to compare and contrast them.", "\"There are many details that need to be considered during the planning and design phase of any application integration project.  These range from the business considerations through technology, and finally, user experiences and support requirements.  While each project is different, some of the common details I consider for each of my designs are the business objectives, application functionality, ease of integration, adherence to standards, costs, vendor reputation, required training, and documentation.  Each of these is weighted differently for each project depending on its importance to the project stakeholders.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What portion of your job involves software development, project management and application integration?", "answers": ["As with any job, your role as an application integration engineer involves doing various tasks throughout the day.  Some of these are directly related to the job, while others are more administrative.  Examples include paperwork, training, meetings, and other activities not related to integrating applications within the organization's IT environment.  It would help if you had a pretty good idea of how much time you spend on the three activities the interviewer is asking about. However, these should not represent your entire day.", "\"My day consists of a variety of different activities.  While some of these are related to application integration, the largest amount of time is spent with non-integration-related tasks that I consider administrative.  Regarding the three you asked about, I spend about 20% of my time developing software, 10% managing projects, and 30% doing work directly related to application integration.  The balance of my day is spent in meetings, paperwork, and training.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "How important is it to perform a security analysis when developing an application integration strategy?", "answers": ["One of the top concerns of any organization is about its IT infrastructure and operation's security.  Companies are well aware of cyber threats and their impact if the organization's information is compromised or security breached by hackers.  During the interview, you will be asked many questions about how you implement IT security protocols in your work.  These can range from your personal practices, such as protecting passwords and not accessing dangerous websites, to more job-related issues such as user authentication, firewalls, and other security technologies.  You can prepare for this question by reviewing common security practices and how you use them.", "\"I consider IT security to be one of the most critical issues I address in them if any application integration project.  While costs and performance of the application are important, if the security is breached, the application's performance is irrelevant, and the costs to remediate the threat will far exceed the total cost of ownership of the application.  Whenever I design a strategy for an application integration platform, I make sure there are adequate security protocols in place to protect the organization's information and infrastructure, and comply with any applicable standards, policies, and regulations.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "How engaged are you with the network architecture and protocols used to support the applications you integrate?", "answers": ["While your title is application integration engineer, your duties will expand beyond software, and you may be asked to participate in projects involving the organization's hardware and network infrastructure.  The interviewer doesn't expect you to have deep expertise in these areas. Still, they do expect you have some familiarity and ability to work with elements of the IT infrastructure in addition to application platforms.  If you don't already have proficiency in networking, it is easy to attain by taking some online classes or even obtaining a Cisco certification.", "\"Understanding how the applications I integrate interact with the hardware and network infrastructure is an important part of my job.  I always look beyond the application's functionality and seek to understand how it will be used and whether the IT infrastructure will support it.  In doing this work, I've become familiar with how computer networks work, their common architectures and components, and the protocols they employ.  Understanding how each of these impacts my application's performance and functionality has helped me increase the accuracy and effectiveness of my work.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What is a Human Machine Interface (HMI), and how do you use it?", "answers": ["While people don't interact directly with every application or IT asset, how humans interact with technology is a key concern for application integration engineers.  The interaction goes beyond just the input and output of information. It also involves the functions the application performs, the results they generate, and how the organization uses these.  The interviewer will ask you about HMI to ensure that you understand this concept and determine how you use it when specifying applications.", "\"Human machine interface, or HMI, refers to how people interact with technology and the benefits they obtain from using it.  Naturally, this involves input devices such as keyboards and mice and output devices such as monitors, audio systems, and printers.  However, HMI extends beyond just the user interface and includes how the technology communicates with other technologies, the operating systems and programming it runs on, the specific types of hardware and networking used, how the databases are constructed, and how the information is presented to the user, in forms, reports, and using other present presentation techniques.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Describe for me how you perform continuous improvement, working with other information technology personnel to increase the application environment's capacity, reliability, and efficiency.", "answers": ["The job of an application integration engineer extends beyond the integration, implementation, and release of the application to production.  Application integration engineers are expected to help the organization implement continuous improvements to the application platforms.  These may include updates and upgrades, patches and bug fixes, and eventually, replacing the application.  Describing how you do this to the interviewer is critical for demonstrating your qualifications for this job.  As always, keep your answer brief and to the point, and be prepared for follow-up questions.", "\"An important part of my job is reviewing the applications regularly to identify opportunities for process improvements.  I am always looking to discover if I can optimize the applications to increase their performance or enable them to better meet the user needs.  I work closely with the vendors to determine if upgrades are available for the applications, whether I need to install patches or bug fixes, and if a new version will be available soon.  I also continually test the application's interactions with other programs and elements of the IT environment to ensure it continues to function as originally designed.  Finally, I meet with the business users to get their input on how well the application meets their needs and if any additional requirements have developed since we originally speced the application.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What motivates you as an application integration engineer?", "answers": ["An interviewer will ask you what motivates you in your career to determine whether you approach this role as a job or as a profession.  A job is something you use to make money and support a lifestyle.  A profession is something you are passionate about and seek to advance within.  Anybody can perform a job if they have the necessary skills and experience.  However, only highly motivated individuals are willing to put in the extra effort and take the steps needed to advance within their profession.  These same actions benefit the organizations they work for.  This is why the interviewer will ask this question.", "\"I am motivated as an application integration engineer by the satisfaction I get from solving difficult challenges, completing projects on time, and witnessing the results of my efforts have on the organization. I've always felt the need to contribute, whether part of a youth sports team, a member of the cast of a school play or a volunteer in a philanthropic organization.  This same need to contribute motivates me to work hard in my profession and exceed the expectations of my organization.  While I appreciate being recognized by management for my achievements, my greatest satisfaction comes from knowing that I've done my very best and achieved what I set out to do.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Why are you the best application integration engineer for us?", "answers": ["This question is much like the one that asks why the organization should hire you.  It is a question you can be prepared for by creating a script.  This variation of the question allows you to quickly review your qualifications and discuss how well you will fit into and contribute to their corporate culture.  Every candidate the company interviews is qualified for the role.  However, every candidate may not be a good fit for the organization.  Focus on this when responding to the question.", "\"I believe I am the best application integration engineer for this job because not only do I possess all the necessary technical qualifications, but I would be a great fit for the organization. I've worked with several other companies similar to yours and understand the importance of collaboration within my department and across the organization.  I never lose sight of the fact that the IT organization supports the business operations of the company.  I work hard to get along with the other departments and communicate complex technical topics in clear, easy-to-understand language.  I also bring a great sense of humor which keeps the working environment light and friendly.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What are the key qualifications for an application integration engineer?", "answers": ["An interviewer is likely to ask you this question early in the interview to begin the conversation, learn more about you, and collect information they can use throughout the interview.  By asking you about the key qualification for this job, they hope to learn that you both understand the qualifications and determine which you feel is important.  The best way to prepare for this question is to review the job description for this and similar positions.  Employers will describe what they consider important for this role.", "\"In my opinion, an application integration engineer should have the skills used to design, implement, and support a company-wide integration strategy for software platforms and data interfaces for the organization's application ecosystem. This can encompass applications hosted on-premise and in the cloud and standard off-the-shelf programs and custom-written applications. Application integration enables independently designed software applications to seamlessly work together. The application integration engineer should be able to  develop platforms, standards, and methodologies that integrate the flow of multiple functions performed by disparate applications.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What are some of the more common applications and tools used in application integration?", "answers": ["As an application integration engineer, you'll use several different applications, tools, and methodologies to perform your job.  The interviewer will likely ask you about these to confirm that you are familiar with them and see whether the tools and applications you use align with the ones their organization is currently employing.  This should be an easy question for you to answer since you use these items every day.  It would be helpful if you researched the organization to determine what tools and applications they use to either align your answer to their current environment or be aware that the ones you use are not the same ones they use.", "\"I use several different tools and applications in my job as an application integration engineer.  These range from standard IT tools and processes to very specific application integration platforms. Examples of the integration platforms I typically use include Jitterbit, Talend, Dell Boomi, and Mulesoft.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "How does API contribute to application integration?", "answers": ["APIs are a critical part of the application integration process.  These are the glue that connects disparate programs so they can exchange data and interoperate.  As an application integration engineer, you should have an in-depth knowledge of APIs, how they work, and how you use them in your job.  You will always be asked about this by the interviewer, so you should prepare your answer and advance.", "\"APIs enable interaction between data, applications, and devices. They deliver data and facilitate connectivity between devices and programs.  I use APIs extensively in my job as an application integration engineer.  The specific APIs I employ are defined by the application the organization uses, their dependencies, how the applications are implemented, and the online programming interface of the organization.  If implemented appropriately, APIs will allow the organization's applications to communicate with backend systems, each other, and the IT hardware the company has deployed.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What is the average time to complete an API integration on a software application once it is initiated?", "answers": ["This may be a difficult question to answer.  The time it takes to complete an API integration will depend on many different factors.  These include the software platform, what other applications the program is interacting with, the hardware it is hosted on, and other factors external to the application itself.  The interviewer will ask you this question not to learn about the specific times but to ensure that you are familiar with the dependencies.  When responding to this, you should note the dependencies and provide one to two examples of a typical time to complete an API integration.", "\"There is no average time to complete an API integration of a software application.  The time it takes depends on many factors, both within and outside of the control of the application integration engineer.  Some of these include the IT environment, the other programs the application is interacting with, the nature of the API, and whether the applications are hosted on-premise or in the cloud.  An example of this variation in integration times is that integrating an HTML version of an (API) may typically take less than an hour to complete. In contrast, integration of the XML version of the same API could take up to 20 hours, due to its complexity.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What is an API, and what function does it perform?", "answers": ["During an application integration engineer interview, you will be asked many questions about APIs.  This is because this technology is used extensively in this job.  Before the interview, you should take some time to review APIs, how they are used, and methodologies for integrating them.  When responding to a question about an API, keep your answers brief and to the point.  The interviewer will request additional information if they need it.", "\"API stands for Application Programming Interface. It functions as a software agent, allowing two or more applications to talk to each other. APIs ensure that the applications will work well together, can exchange data, and can be used on a variety of different platforms, including computers, phones, and tablets. APIs also allow the software to interface with hardware components such as printers.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What are some of the jobs you've performed in the past that have helped qualify you for an application integration engineer's role?", "answers": ["Nobody starts off their career as an application integration engineer.  This profession requires a great deal of experience, training, and the acquisition of a wide variety of skills.  Although it is probably reflected on your resume, the interviewer will ask you about some of your prior experiences and provide additional information about how these have contributed to your qualifications for this role.", "\"I worked several different jobs before becoming an application integration engineer. These are summarized in my resume.  I don't think I would be qualified for this role, having not acquired the necessary skills and experience through these other jobs.  I started my career as a systems administrator, maintaining the IT infrastructure for companies, including both the hardware and the applications the company used.  I then moved on to a role as a software engineer.  This provided me with a great deal of background about software applications, their dependencies, and how they integrate into the hardware and software environment of the organization.  Next, I spent time as a software consultant, making recommendations about what software applications a company should adopt and how they could quickly integrate into their existing environment.  I believe all of these roles prepared me for this job.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Please walk me through the steps involved in a typical application integration project.", "answers": ["In addition to learning about your skills, experience, and knowledge, the interviewer will be interested in the processes you use.  This provides them information about how you go about doing your job and if your processes align well with the organization.  Before going to an interview, you should research the company to learn about its IT processes and procedures.  Sources for this information include the job description, the company's website, and speaking with both past and present IT employees.", "\"As an application integration engineer, I work on all phases of the integration process. This includes planning, design, and implementation of an application integration strategy.  The process starts with determining the organization's needs, characterizing the IT environment, and specifying additional applications to be integrated into its operations. Once my recommendations are approved, I proceed with the planning, implementation, project management, and testing activities. The final step is creating documentation for the process so that the systems engineers know how to solve potential issues.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Do you feel that documentation is a critical part of an application integration engineer's job, and if so, why?", "answers": ["Every job involves paperwork.  This is especially true for the role of an application integration engineer.  Documenting what you do in the planning phase, project management work, during testing, and ongoing support is critical to ensuring that the application environment has been integrated correctly and can be easily supported while in production.  It would be best if you were prepared to discuss how you document the various tasks you perform and advocate the importance of documentation.", "\"Documentation is a critical component of my work.  Without this, I would not be able to properly integrate applications into the company's IT environment and provide the information needed for the systems engineering team to support them.  Documentation is created in each project phase, including information gathering, project planning, execution, testing, and deployment.  In each of these phases, I create documents that make it easy for my team to execute our tasks.  All this culminates in support documentation used to maintain, upgrade, and optimize the application platforms.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Do you have experience performing a cost justification analysis for an application integration project, and can you describe how you do this?", "answers": ["A key talent any application integration engineer should possess is the ability to cost-justify the application upgrade, optimization, and integration recommendations they make.  Knowing how to do this requires both technical, financial, and business skills.  You need to consider all the costs, including the initial purchase price, the cost to integrate the application, and finally, the ongoing support costs.  Together these are known as the total cost of ownership or TCO.  Discussing these concepts with the interviewer will demonstrate your qualifications for this position.", "\"I have a great deal of experience performing feasibility studies, estimating the total cost of ownership for an application integration project, and providing a cost justification for my recommendations, using accepted financial practices to determine a project's viability.  Elements of my estimates include the business drivers, estimating the cost and scope of the project, running the financial modeling, and performing a comprehensive financial analysis for the project. This required me to learn about financial concepts such as return on investment and net present value.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Can you describe some of the standards, templates, and guidelines you've developed in your past roles as an application integration engineer?", "answers": ["As an application integration engineer, a key part of your job is establishing standards your organization uses when considering any IT project, especially those involved in purchasing or integrating a new application platform.  Having in-depth knowledge and understanding of standards, guidelines, and templates demonstrates your expertise in this area and your ability to continue to perform this work if hired by the organization.", "\"One of the more important contributions I make to the organizations I work for is to establish standards, guidelines, and templates for technology adaptation.  To do this work properly, I need to be familiar with a wide range of industry standards, governmental regulations, and vendor guidelines.  These include programming language and the operating system standards, customer protocols, vendor product standards, electrical codes and ISA standards, and many others.  I work hard to maintain my knowledge of current standards since new ones are always being created and existing ones upgraded.  I also use informal guidelines and standard templates to help make the work my organization and the entire company performs easier and more consistent.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Tell me about how you create detailed equipment specifications and data sheets, vendor selection criteria.", "answers": ["Since most of the projects you work on will involve making recommendations for specific applications and software, you should be skilled at developing detailed specifications, summarizing vendor product datasheets, and establishing standard vendor selection criteria.  The interviewer is interested in learning how you do this and how effective the materials you create are.  As with any technical question, keep your answer direct and to the point.  The interviewer will ask you a follow-up question if they need additional information.", "\"Creating specifications for the applications for the organization needs to accomplish its business objectives is a key part of my job.  This process is supported by my ability to understand and summarize product features and benefits and establish standard vendor selection criteria to quickly analyze my options and choose the correct partner. My ability to do this required me to become intimately familiar with a wide range of computing technologies, understand the business applications an organization needs and learn how to quickly ascertain a product's features and benefits.  Having worked with and selected a great many vendors, I understand this process, and I've created a detailed set of criteria which allows me to quickly select them effectively.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Can you describe the data structure layout and data flow model elements you consider when creating an application integration strategy?", "answers": ["Virtually every single application requires data.  When developing an application integration strategy, you need to be keenly aware of how the data is used, how it flows between the application and other programs, where it is stored, how data is accessed, and many other details.  Describing to the interviewer what you consider and how you include the data structure layout in your application integration design is critical to demonstrate your qualification for this job.", "\"Next to the functionality of the application, the data structure associated with it is the second most important consideration.  Virtually every application will need to access data in a specific manner.  Mapping the data flow, understanding the data structure, what control systems are used, and many other issues must be considered during an application integration project's design and planning phase.  I consider specific data-related issues, including data security, quality, storage and retrieval, database software, and documentation.  Fortunately, I've become adept at this and have a deep portfolio of resources to analyze the data flow and integrate it into my design.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "How do you implement a data transfer methodology that maximizes throughput and ensures data integrity?", "answers": ["In addition to the data the application uses, it also must exchange information with other devices, programs, and users.  Implementing an effective data transfer methodology that optimizes the application's functionality is another key talent an application integration engineer should possess.  During the interview, you will be asked about the many different skills you need to do this job.  When discussing them, use very basic, non-technical language and avoid acronyms and industry jargon.  Whenever you answer a question, the interviewer judges how well you communicate complex technical concepts to individuals with non-technical backgrounds.", "\"How the application uses and exchanges data is a critical consideration when developing an application integration strategy.  Fortunately, the industry has created standard protocols and methodologies which address this.  However, I still need to consider which standards are appropriate for the application and how well they will integrate into the organization's IT infrastructure.  Specific items I consider and address include network protocols, APIs, operating systems, data mapping, industry standards, application interoperability, and of course, data security.  While I can't optimize each of these, I make sure that the data transfer adheres to the organization's requirements and performs as well as it can within the IT environment.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Can you describe how you create and use a test plan to determine an application integration project's compliance with the stakeholder requirements?", "answers": ["One of the last phases of an application integration project is testing and verification.  While some testing is performed throughout the entire process, most testing is done just before releasing the application into production.  The interviewer expects you to be knowledgeable of testing methodologies and procedures.  While you may not actually perform the tests, you should be aware of what will be done and how to design an application integration project to adhere to the standards and pass the different types of tests it will be subjected to.", "\"Creating a test plan to confirm the application's adherence to standards and compliance with the stakeholder' requirements begins during the discovery and planning phases of the project.  This is where ere the user requirements are established.  Knowing these and the type of tests the application will be subjected to after integration helps me develop the implementation and testing plan.  Sometimes I develop the testing plan first so I can use it to guide the implementation strategy.  Components of the testing plan include the techniques to be used, the standards the application must adhere to, the performance metrics it must meet, how it interoperates with other components of the IT infrastructure, and other design components, which will be verified before releasing it to production.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What major challenges and problems did you face in your last position?", "answers": ["No matter how much you enjoy your work, every job involves challenges and issues you need to solve.  The interviewer will ask you about these to make sure that you are approaching this position realistically, not afraid of facing a challenge and learn about how you achieve this.  Your answer should reflect your ability to overcome challenges and provide an example of how you've done this in the past.", "\"Overcoming challenges is a key part of an application integration engineer's job.  Regardless of how well you plan a project, something unexpected always occurs and needs to be resolved.  While I don't look for problems, I enjoy challenges that require me to innovate and be creative to resolve them.  For example, I encountered an issue with one of my tools to integrate an application in my last job. It didn't operate properly with the other tools the team was using.  After some thought, it occurred to me that there may be a patch available from the vendor.  I contacted them and confirmed that they had a solution to this issue.  I quickly applied the patch into the tool, and it worked perfectly.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "How do you evaluate success?", "answers": ["There are many ways you can evaluate success.  Many of these are formal and involve metrics such as completing projects on time and under budget, achieving cost savings, attaining certifications, and other accomplishments which can be measured.  Success can also be evaluated by qualitative measures such as how well you are respected within the organization, whether people have confidence in you, and how your contributions have helped the organization achieve its business objectives.  You can respond to this question by describing either the quantitative or qualitative measures of success you use to gauge how well you are performing.", "\"I evaluate my professional success several ways.  I track how well I perform on the projects I am assigned to and whether I'm completing my tasks on time and to the designated specifications.  The organizations I've worked for use the same metrics.  However, I also gauge my success based on the feedback I get from my supervisors, their willingness to assign me more challenging tasks, and how often I assist my associates in finishing their projects and tasks.  While these are harder to quantify, I believe they better represent the contributions are making to the organization.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": ["This is a common question asked during an interview.  It is a type of question you can prepare for by creating a script.  Your answer should discuss the benefits you will bring to the organization, the problems you can help them solve, and how you can help them make money, save money, or save time.  You may also want to touch on how well you will fit into their corporate culture and contribute to it.  Avoid talking about your qualifications, experience, and skills.  By inviting you to the interview, they have already acknowledged these and their fit for the position.", "\"The main reason you should hire me is I can help your organization optimize its IT operations and how they support the company's business activities.  I can quickly integrate the applications you're adding to your IT infrastructure, test them to ensure they are functioning correctly, and provide documentation the systems engineering team can use to support them.  Once hired, I can monitor your existing applications to ensure that they are continuing to provide the benefits you originally purchased them for and, if necessary, make the appropriate upgrades or replacements.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Ten years from now, where do you see yourself?", "answers": ["An interviewer will ask you this question to determine if you have a career plan and hope to advance within the organization.  While individuals don't need to want to advance, a desire to move up indicates to the interviewer that you are motivated, willing to learn new things, and will put in extra effort to move to the next level within the organization.  Companies prefer to hire highly motivated individuals rather than those who are satisfied remaining in one position for their entire career.  Even if your ambition does not go beyond this immediate role, you should be able to describe where you'd like to be professionally a decade from now.", "\"Ten years from now, I see myself leading a team of application integration engineers in this organization. I'm very excited about the immediate opportunity and look forward to joining the application integration engineer team. I would also like to advance into a leadership role that requires more experience, skills, and the willingness to assume more responsibility. I've heard that your organization encourages its employees to acquire additional skills and experience and provides opportunities for advancement.  This is one of the reasons I was attracted to this role.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "What excites you the most about a career as an application integration engineer?", "answers": ["This is a typical opening question the interviewer will use early in the interview to start the conversation, learn more about your background, and collect information they can use throughout the interview.  You should be prepared for this type of question and other common questions used during an interview.  One way you can do this is to review these questions and answer them in your own words before going to the interview.", "\"I have always had a great desire to learn new things and figure out how things work.  This thirst for knowledge and understanding of how different technologies work together helped me develop basic computer engineering skills.  I became very excited when I learned that my natural tendency to connect technologies could be turned into an application integration engineer career.  When I entered college, I immediately enrolled in a program that would help me acquire the skills and background needed for this profession.  Once I obtained my first position as an application integration engineer, I knew I had chosen the right career, and I've never looked back.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Integration+Engineer", "question": "Describe the most creative work related project you completed.", "answers": ["When an interviewer asks you this question, they hope to understand the scope of the projects you've worked on and whether your experience aligns with the needs of the position they're trying to fill.  Before coming to the interview, you should research the job posting and the organization to understand the position's requirements and the business's operations.  You then answer this and other questions within the context of their needs, so they quickly understand that you're the right candidate for this role.", "\"The most creative project I worked on involved integrating the HR module into an organization's existing SAP system. Since the HR module had data dependencies across the entire company and specific dependencies with the legal, production, executive management, and sales organizations, integrating it properly and connecting it to the other SAP modules was challenging. This was compounded by the fact that I had never done this before. I decided to form a project team comprised of my IT associates, the senior HR staff, and the SAP tech support team. By collaborating, we were able to identify the data dependencies, create links to the other SAP modules, test the software, and release it into production. I am proud of how I creatively developed a solution to a challenging project and the knowledge I acquired which helped me with similar situations I encountered since then.\""]}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "What major challenges and problems did you face at your last position?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "Why should we hire you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "Why do you want to leave your current employer?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "What have your achievements been to date?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "Tell me about an accomplishment you are most proud of.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "Give an example of a time when you made a mistake because you did not listen well to what someone had to say.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "How do you keep track of work so that it gets done on time?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "Describe the most creative work related project you completed.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "What makes you passionate about being an Application Programmer?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Application+Programmer", "question": "What are you doing to keep current in technology?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What is RBAC?", "answers": ["RBAC stands for Role-Based Access Control and provides an Azure administrator to configure access to an Azure resource(s) to a individual, group, or application, assigned to a particular role.  The administrator assigns individuals, groups or applications to a particular role.  This role has a scope (which can include a management group, subscription, resource group or an individual resource).  Role assignments can be inherited.  For example, if an individual is assigned access to a resource group, that user has access to perform actions for all resources (VMs, storage, networks,etc) within that group."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Name the top 5 security tasks you can implement prior to a production installation.", "answers": ["1.  Enabling the Azure Security Center (ASC) - the ASC provides security monitoring of on/off-prem resources, providing security recommendations across your resources;  It utilizes machine learning algorithms to detect and prevent malware installations.  The ASC can be enabled through the Azure portal, and searching for the \"Security Center\" option.\n\t2.  Validate your input - It is a best practice to add validation to your html input boxes in your web applications.  You can add client-side masking to make sure only accepted value-types are submitted.  When executing SQL queries upon submission, always use parameterized queries or stored stored procedures, to avoid sql injection attacks.  Additionally, alway encode any output to be presented to the user on screen.\n\t3.  Use Azure Key vault to store your keys/secrets.  You could then programmatically access the sensitive data through an api call versus accessing data directly from a configuration file, for example.\n\t4.  Keep your application frameworks up-to-date.\n\t5.  Continually keep track of the latest security vulnerabilities.  Be aware of the Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE - https://cve.mitre.org/) list and expeditiously implement the recommended fixes."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What facility does Azure offer to minimize application downtime during deployments?", "answers": ["Azure deployment slots are separate environments, approximating different app service instances.  With deployment slots, you are able to create separate development, testing and production environments, each having their own distinct hostnames.  For example, once your application has been thoroughly tested in the testing slot, you can swap the production slot with the testing slot.  This happens instantaneously, with no impact to the end user.  If there is an issue with the new production version (ie. an uncaught exception condition), you can easily and instantaneously swap the old production version back.  This facility is only available for the basic, standard, premium and isolated pricing tiers."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What options do you have as a developer, for implementing business logic in the cloud and why would you do so?", "answers": ["Azure app services provide the ability to implement business processes in the cloud.  A use case for doing so could be to integrate 2 or more disparate back-offices systems into one cohesive workflow.  Let's say an online retailer of product 1 acquires another retailer of a complementary product, each with separate ordering and inventory management system.  Azure simplifies this integration by supplying two designs for connecting business processes:\n\n-Design first:  \n\t-Microsft Power Automate\n\t-Logic Apps\n\nCode first:\n\t-WebJobs and WebJobs SDK\n\t-Azure Functions"]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe a use case for implementing an Azure Event Hub.", "answers": ["When the volume of source data is expected to grow during certain peak time periods, an event pipeline should be available to handle those data packets until the consumer(s) of the packets are able to handle them.  In this case, an Azure Event hub is an appropriate service to implement."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What is an appropriate use case for an Azure Event grid?", "answers": ["An event grid enables you to aggregate multiple events generated from Azure resources and provides a routing mechanism from those sources to multiple destinations.  This follows the publisher/subscriber paradigm.  A use case for an event grid could be the creation of a notification workflow when changes occur to a virtual machine, for example.  You can then use an Azure logic app to handle the event and send an email to system administrators, depending upon the specific criteria within the logic app.  Event handlers can be Azure Functions, Azure Logic Apps, Azure Automation, Azure Event Hubs, and Azure Service Bus."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What Azure service enables you, as a developer, to conveniently allow and manage access to your function?", "answers": ["Azure API management (APIM) service allow developers to conveniently manage access to Azure functions.  This model enables external partners, for example, to make secure http calls to internal functions or microservices.  The steps to do so are as follows:\n\nA.  Either through the command line or Azure portal, create your http-triggered, Azure function apps.\nB.  Through the portal, search for the function of interest, and select it.\nC.  In the middle pane in the API section, find and select \"API Management\".\nD.  In the right pane, find and click on the \"Create new\" link, enter the appropriate details and click \"Create\".\nE.  After it has been created, click \"Link API\".  In the next screen, click \"Select\" to continue.\nF.  In the next screen, \"Create from Function App\", change the \"API URL suffix\" to an appropriate name and click \"Create\".\n\nAPIM enables you to monitor the performance and apply security policies to each microservice.  You can also define the output format for each.  For example, you can enforce transformation of XML output to JSON."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What are the steps required for creating an Azure function through Visual Studio?", "answers": ["Though you can directly create functions in your Azure subscription through the portal, you may wish to first create and test your function locally.  Visual Studio affords this opportunity and allows you to develop your code in C#.\n\nSteps:\n1.  Create a new project and select the \"Azure Functions\" template.  \n2.  On the next page, select the type of trigger to implement.  This will create the Azure Function application, to which you add your specific function.  Remember that the Azure Function app acts as a container, to which you can add functions.\n3.  Right-click on the newly created project, select \"Add\" and select \"New Azure Function\".  Then, name the function.\n4.  You will next get prompted for the type of trigger to implement.\n5.  You can next debug your function as you would any other application.\n6.  If you implemented an HTTP trigger, running the application will display a command window which will show the URL of your functions.\n7.  With an HTTP trigger function, you would simply make a request to that URL passing the appropriate parameters, through a browser or CURL."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "How are you able to persist state and use functions to create a long-running workflow?", "answers": ["Durable functions allows you to chain together a series of functions, simulating a lengthly workflow and persisting values from one function to another.  There are several approaches to implementing durable functions.  In the simplest case, you can implement \"function chaining\", where the output of one function becomes the input of the next and the last function returns your final result:\n\n--->input parameters ---->function 1: output1 ----> (input1)function 2: output2 ---->(input2)function 3:  final result"]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What is an Azure Function and provide a use case for implementing one?", "answers": ["An Azure Function allows developers to design and code custom functionality, in a variety of languages (C#, F#, JavaScript, Python, and PowerShell Core).  You can create your code locally on Visual Studio or use Azure Cloud Shell's online code generation editor.  You would then create an Azure Function application through the Azure Portal.  The function is connected to inputs and outputs through \"bindings\", which connect a source and target to your function.  It can then be executed through a number of \"triggers\", which can be the addition of records to a CosmosDB or storage blob, an http request as well as others.  It can also be set up as a scheduled trigger by implementing a timer.  This capability frees the developer from implementing any infrastructure to host the function and allows them to focus on simply developing the logic.  This design would be ideal for monitoring smart devices (IOT) in the field, for example.  The devices can be bound as a datasource to your function, which can then monitor changes in temperature, humidity or other data you wish to analyze."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What are the different types of triggers for an Azure function?", "answers": ["- A timer trigger\nUse case - create a trigger that executes when an appointment is made and then a timer trigger as a reminder for day-of appointments\nSteps:  A.  Create a function app (A function app is like a container to which you can add functions) and then deploy it.  B. To the function app, add a function and to it, add a timer trigger from the select a template list.  You can then edit the trigger and specify the interval to execute the trigger.  \n - HTTP trigger\nThis trigger executes a function when it receives an http request.  After creating and deploying your function app, create your function and select the HTTP trigger type from the template list.  A \"Get function URL\" link is available to copy the generated link which will trigger the function.\n- Storage trigger\nThis trigger is executed when a file is uploaded to a storage account, most commonly blob storage.  A blob storage account is designed to hold large amounts of unstructured data."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "How are you able to develop and test Azure functions without using an IDE?", "answers": ["You can use Azure Core Tools to create and test Azure functions locally.  It is a command-line tool which will allow you to perform the following:\n\t-locally create the files and folders needed for function development\n\t-execute the function on your local workstation and allow you to test and debug it\n\t-publish your function to the Azure app service for production use"]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe a webhook and how you would use it in an Azure function?", "answers": ["A webhook is an http-triggered callback that has an associated URL, which is requested when a configured event is triggered.  A common use cases for a webhook event is source code repository changes.  In a DevOps environment, you can configure an webhook-enabled, Azure function to respond to changes in a GitHub.  GitHub has a webhook event, Gollum, that is specified for this purpose.  In the payload URL Box of the GitHub UI, add the URL of the Azure function that will respond when the event is triggered."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What Azure mechanism could you use to implement a persistent connection between a datasource input and your Azure function?", "answers": ["SignalR is a series of technologies that allow 2-way communication between a publishing datasource and any subscribing clients.  Through this technology, a persistent connection can be established between a CosmosDB, for example, and an Azure function allowing changes in the database to be monitored by the function which can then respond accordingly."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "List the different messaging mechanisms available through Azure, which allow robust communication among disparate systems.", "answers": ["When you have several disparate systems that need to communicate with one another in order to complete a particular workflow, there may be times when this workflow is disrupted due to packets being dropped between one or more systems. An example of this could be a system where you have the following components:\n\n\ta.  a web front end\n\tb.  a server-side function\n\tc.  a database\n\nIn this scenario, Azure provides message and event modules to facilitate communication between and among separate components."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What is the difference between an event and a message?", "answers": ["A message contains the raw data, which is meant to be consumed by another component.  It is not just a reference to the data.  An event implements the publisher/subscriber or pub/sub model, in which a source 'publishes' or broadcasts an event or something that has occurred at the source.  Interested components or subscribers can then respond accordingly to the event.  This subscription is handled by an Azure Event Grid or Azure Event Hub.  It is important to know the difference between the message and event models and know which one to implement for a given use case."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What are the different messaging types and how would you decide which design to use?", "answers": ["There are 2 main types of messages, which are implemented through the Azure Service bus.  A message queue allows the temporary storage of messages from one source to one destination.  A message topic is similar to a queue, except that more than one destination is allowed.  In other words, each message can be delivered to multiple receivers in a topic.  Additionally, a subscriber can filter a message to only those that may be relevant.  The anticipated message and holding queue sizes is an important considerations.  If the size of a message will be greater the 64kb but less than 256kb and the queue size will be smaller than 80 gb, then a service bus queue would be appropriate.  Otherwise, a storage queue should be implemented."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe the process for implementing messaging with Azure Queue storage.", "answers": ["#1:  Create a storage account - login to the Azure portal, create a storage resource by completing the required information\n#2:  Once your storage account is created, retrieve the connection string of the account which can be found in the Portal ---> Settings ---> Access keys section of the portal account.  Save this for later.\n\n//#3:    Instantiate the connection to the Queue -- \n\n\t\tCloudStorageAccount account = CloudStorageAccount.Parse(connectionString);\n\n\t\tCloudQueueClient client = account.CreateCloudQueueClient();\n\n\t\tCloudQueue queue = client.GetQueueReference(\"myqueue\");\n\n\t\t//b. The sender will programatically create the Queue - \n\t\tCloudQueue queue; // create an instance of the queue\n\n\t\tawait queue.CreateIfNotExistsAsync();// only create it if it doesn't already exist\n\n\t//#4:    Add a message to the Queue -- \n\t\tvar message = new CloudQueueMessage(\"your message here\");\n\n\t\tCloudQueue queue;\t\n\n\t\twait queue.AddMessageAsync(message);\n\n\t//#5:     Retrieve and delete a message from the Queue --\n\n\t\t// in your client subscriber code:\n\t\tCloudQueue queue;\n\n\t\tCloudQueueMessage message = await queue.GetMessageAsync();\n\n\t\tif (message != null)\n\t\t{\n    \t\t// Process the message\n\n    \t\tawait queue.DeleteMessageAsync(message);\n\t\t}"]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What are the general datatypes that could be expected in a cloud environment?", "answers": ["a.  Structured data - this is the type of data hosted in a relational database, such as MS SQL Server.  This data is organized in tables comprised of rows and column and retrieved using structure query language (SQL)\nb.  Semi-structure data - this data does not fit into tables with rows and field names, but rather are identified by tags in key/pair values.  Common formats include XML, JSON, and YAML and are also referred to NoSQL data.\nc.  No-structure data - These data have no organization and are often in binary formats.  Files such as images, executables, audio or video files may be tagged, but the data itself is unstructured."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What steps should you consider when implementing an Azure virtual machine?", "answers": ["- Consider the network in which the VM will reside\n\tWill your VMs connect to resources within the same virtual network, external resources or both?  This will come into play when setting up your address spaces/subnets and security.  Once created, any change would incur significant time to test and re-implement.\n - Plan the VM deployment\n\tWhat OS will you use?  How much space should be allocated?  What is the purpose of the VM (app server, database server, etc )?  What ports are to be opened?  What will you name the VM?  This last point may sound trivial, but the better the naming convention, the easier it will be to quickly identify it and its purpose.  Once created, the name is not a trivial thing to change.\n - Decide the location for the VM -- You will want to place the VM(s) in a region, as close to the end users as possible, to improve performance.  There may also be legal and compliance restrictions to be considered.\n - Understanding the pricing model-- You will need to consider 2 metrics, compute and storage costs.  With the pay-as-you-go model, you/your company will incur charges for as much time your VM is in operation.  The hourly price varies based upon VM size and operating system, with Windows machines being more expensive than Linux machines due to licensing costs.  You can possibly save money by creating reserved VM instances if you need to have the VM always on and can commit to your VM being active for at least one year.  In this case, you prepay for the VM.  Each virtual hard disk (VHD) allocated to your VM incurs a cost for the space that is being used."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What is the MEAN stack?", "answers": ["MEAN is the acronym for MongoDB, Express.js, AngularJS and Node.js development stack.  If your expertise is in Javascript and NoSQL databases, this would be the appropriate technology stack in which to develop your web application. This environment is supported on both the Windows and Linux OS."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe the process for building an ASP.net app in Visual Studio and deploying it to an Azure app service.", "answers": ["1.  Configure your VS environment to include the appropriate 'workloads'.  A workload is a pre-defined set of tools in Visual Studio, for building certain types of applications, use specific languages, or develop for specific platforms. So for an ASP.net application, you will need to make sure that the ASP.net and web development workload is installed.  For Azure hosting, the Azure workload should be included as well. \n2.  Create and build your ASP.net application.\n3.  Create and deploy an Azure App service.  You will need to consider the level of service plan, the region where your app is to be hosted, and your pricing/reliability plans.  You should also select the resource group to which the service will be assigned.\n4.  Deploy your application.  Once the app is built and tested, you will select the deployment target, which in this case will be Azure.  During the publishing process, you will enter the specifics of the app service created in the previous step."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What are the options for accommodating high traffic usage scenarios with your web application?", "answers": ["Scaling out - You can adjust your app service plan to add more instances, up to the limit allowed by your service plan.  If you notice the following application characteristics:\nincrease in CPU utilization, memory occupancy, disk queue length, response time length or the number of failed request, you should consider scaling out.  \nScaling up - If you still notice an increase in any/all of the parameters above and the scaled out instances within the app service pricing plan is reaching the limit, scaling up is the next option.  In this case, you can increase the memory allocations and processing power for the instances within your service plan.\nIn both cases, these adjustments can be made through the Azure portal by opening up your app service plan resources and adjusting the scaling out or scaling up parameters as needed."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe the different options for creating an Azure SQL database.", "answers": ["Azure SQL Database is a (platform-as-a-service) PaaS option, removing you as a developer or DBA, from the responsibility of standing up and maintaining the infrastructure required for hosting a SQL Server instance.  As such, you only need to worry about the design of your database and the different service level options.  Here are the different deployment options:\n\t- a single database:  priced and managed per database\n\t- elastic pools:  priced as a group of databases managed together and share common set of resources\n\t- hyperscale:  this option is based upon a single database, but allows for size greater than the 4 TB limit normally assigned to a regular Azure database\n\nThere are two purchasing options:\n\t- per Database Transaction Unit (DTU), in which pricing is based upon compute, I/O and storage options\n\t\t-within this option, you can purchase the Basic, Standard, and Premium service levels\n\t- per vCore (virtual Core), which allows you to purchase specified vCore according to your database workload\n\t\t        - within this option, you can purchase the following service tiers\n\t\t\t-general purpose:  for general purpose workloads\n\t\t\t-business critical:  this level offers the lowest latency among the three and is for higher performing workloads.  Storage is hosted on local SSDs instead of Azure blob storage.\n\t\t\t-hyperscale:  this level accommodates the databases requiring greater than 4 TB of storage, up to 100 TB."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe ways in which to secure data in-transit and data at rest.", "answers": ["Encrypting disk drives is the best way to secure data at rest.  Azure provides the facility, Microsoft Azure Disk Encryption.  On Windows machines, encryption is based upon BitLocker technology.  Linux VM disks can also be encrypted, using the Linux DM-Crypt feature of Azure encryption.  Azure storage and Azure SQL Server have encryption at rest turned on by default.\nEncryption in transit is accomplished by enabling SSL/TLS protocols during data exchange.  For data exchange between on-premises and cloud resources, a VPN tunnel is recommended.  On premises to cloud VPN configurations can be further modified as follows:\n\nSite-to-site VPN -- should be enabled for multiple on-premises workstations accessing Azure resources\n\nPoint-to-site VPN -- should be enabled for an individual on-premises workstation accessing Azure resources\n\nAzure Express Route -- should be enabled for large datasets.  This requires a WAN link from on-prem to cloud infrastructure."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What are resource groups and how would you use them?", "answers": ["Azure resource groups are logical containers to which any resource (VM, Storage account, VNet, etc) is assigned.  Resource groups cannot be nested and a resource can only be assigned to a single resource group, however, you can move a resource between resource groups.  You can use them to implement organization within your enterprise as follows:\n\n- You can group resources by type, location or usage\n- Project life cycle.  For example, your company would like to develop an application proof-of-concept, whose resources would be only needed temporarily, these resources can be assigned to a resource group.  After the project is over and the resources are no longer needed, the resource group can be deleted, effectively removing all the resources contained therein.\n-Authorization:  Resource groups are a scope for implementing role-based access control (RBAC).  For example, all VNets can be contained with a particular resource group and only network administrators (those assigned t an network admin role) would have access to that resource group."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe the different methods for securing your Azure SQL Database.", "answers": ["You can implement firewall rules at two levels, at the server level and database level.  At the server level, this can be adjusted through the firewall pane in the Azure portal.  You can select \"on/off\" to allow/disallow access to Azure services, or you can specify IP address rules, which are based on specific public IP ranges.  Database-level firewall rules can be configured only through IP address specification.  These rules allow access to a specific database and are stored in the database itself.  You can secure user user access through authentication implementation, either through SQL authentication or integration with Azure Active Directory.  By implementing authorization, you can further restrict a user to access only a specific database or database objects.  For example, say there is a specific user in the database, User1.  \n\n\t//The following SQL query allows User1 to read data:\n\n\tALTER ROLE db_datareader ADD MEMBER User1;\n\tGO;\n\n\t// This statement will disallow User1 from selecting data from Schema.Table1\n\tDENY SELECT ON Schema.Table1 TO User1\n\tGO"]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "Describe the process for locally setting up Azure CLI what commands you would use to create a resource group.", "answers": ["It is important to know that there are a couple of options of creating and managing Azure resources.  In addition to using the Azure portal, Azure provides the CLI, or command line interface, a locally installed application that allows you to connect to your Azure subscription to create and manage your resources.  You can run the CLI on a Mac, Linux or Windows machine.  \n\na.  Install the CLI:  To install Azure CLI on a Windows machine, download the installer from here,  https://aka.ms/installazurecliwindows  and execute the msi file.  Next, verify the installation by opening up a powershell session and execute the command, az --version, which will display the version of the CLI that was installed.\n\nb.  Create a resource group:  First login by executing this,  'az login', and enter your credentials.  Then you would execute 'az group create' followed by the unique name of the resource group you wish create.  Once this is completed, you can then use the CLI to create new resources and add them to the resource group."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What other desktop tool could you use to create automation scripts, particularly if you are a Windows developer?", "answers": ["Windows PowerShell (PS) is a command-line tool that allows the developer to automate Windows System operations and other repetitive system tasks.  In order to interact with Azure resources, PowerShell version 5.0 or higher is required.  You can execute, $PSVersionTable.PSVersion, on the command line to determine your PS version.  Additionally, you'll need to install Azure PowerShell module (Az) which contains the appropriate cmdlets to work with Azure features."]}, {"topic": "Azure+Developer", "question": "What Azure facility can you use to appropriately categorize resources and provide a use case for doing so.", "answers": ["Applying tags to individual resources will make it easier to search for and identify resources that should be logically grouped together.  For example, you would assign a  tag named \"environment\", in which that value can be \"development\", \"QA\" or \"production\".  By assigning those resources (VMs, for example) with the appropriate environment tag, you can quickly search for those resources to ensure that they are placed in the correct resource group and possibly avoid accidental deletion of production resources.  Another use case for tags can be for the assignment of resources to certain departments for billing purposes.  In this case, you can quickly search for resources that fall under the responsibility of the Marketing department and then forward those invoices accordingly."]}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "What negative thing would your last boss say about you?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "Who designed the original Basic programming language?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "What can you do for this company?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "How long would you expect to work for us if hired?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "What can you do for us that other candidates can't?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "How do you handle stressful situations?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "Give me examples of ideas you've had and implemented?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "What challenges are you looking for in a position?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "Tell me about Basic.", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+Basic", "question": "Why is Basic still important today?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "Why is ColdFusion important today?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "When did you begin programming in ColdFusion?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "Do you know why ColdFusion is important to our development team?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "What are the databases that are supported by ColdFusion applications?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "Why programming?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "What exactly is ColdFusion?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "What are your career goals?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "What is your greatest strength as a programmer?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "What is your greatest weakness as a programmer? What are you doing to improve it?", "answers": []}, {"topic": "Programming+ColdFusion", "question": "What have you done recently to become a better programmer?", "answers": []}]